<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>drew.lanen.ga</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>https://drew.lanen.ga/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://drew.lanen.ga/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2016 22:57:25 -0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2016 22:57:25 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>bash in R</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There are times when putting reusable code in your own &lt;a href=&quot;http://hilaryparker.com/2014/04/29/writing-an-r-package-from-scratch/&quot;&gt;personal R package&lt;/a&gt; is useful — saving yourself time by structuring repetitive tooling, sharing difficult or specific implementations of hard problems to help others hate life less, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is kind of just a one off — and doesn’t fit in either of those two categories — but I thought I’d share it here, since I’ll probably eventually come back to it and I think it could be useful for others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you just want to load bash scripts in R — in my particular current case, mainly just to load environment variables from my &lt;code&gt;.bash_profile&lt;/code&gt; — like for cron, running scripts in a cluster, etc.  But I don’t want to pass them as arguments to some script, and it doesn’t seem like &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/yihui/runr&quot;&gt;runr&lt;/a&gt; is doing what I want (yet).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this is a snippet that will load environment variables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&quot;https://gist.github.com/drewlanenga/22965c57f560ff85c589.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’d be nice if it would load other nice &lt;code&gt;bash&lt;/code&gt;-y things, like functions, aliases, etc., and somehow made them available in the current session, but that might also be unnecessary.  (That is, I haven’t yet found it necessary…)&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://drew.lanen.ga/bash-in-R/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://drew.lanen.ga/bash-in-R/</guid>
        
        
        <category>general</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
